[{"question":"<p><strong>A mango fruit drops from a branch 10m above the ground. Just before hitting the ground its velocity is? (g=10m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100 m\/s","5\u221a2 m\/s","10\u221a2 m\/s","20\u221a2 m\/s"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A light wave of frequency 5 x 10<sup>14<\/sup> Hz moves through water which has a refractive index of -3. Calculate the wavelength in water if the velocity of light in air is 3 x 10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.5 x 10<sup>7<\/sup>m","6.0 x 10<sup>-7<\/sup>m","1.7 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>m","2.2 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An isolated conducting sphere whose radius is 6.85cm has a charge 1.25nC. How much potential energy is stored in the electric field of the charged conductor ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100nJ","101nJ","103nJ","104nJ"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the correct statement(s)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Resistance is a property of an object","Resistivity is the property of a material","Resistance is a property of a material","Resistivity is the property of an object"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><b>A common flashing bulb is rated 0.30A and 2.9V. If the resistance of the tungsten bulb filament at temperature 200C is 1. 1 \u2126, find the temperature of the filament when the bulb is on<\/b><br><\/p>","options":["1.1 x 10<sup>7 0<\/sup>C","1.8x10<sup>3 0<\/sup>C","1.5x10<sup>5 0<\/sup>C","1.7x10<sup>2 0<\/sup>C"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Thermal energy is&nbsp; produced in a resistor at a rate of 100 W when the current is 3.00 A. Find the resistance.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11.0\u2126","11.1\u2126","11.5\u2126","11.3\u2126"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the quantity of electricity required to deposit 64.Og of copper from copper (II) chloride (Cu=64, IF=96500C)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.09 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>C","1.93 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>C","9.65 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>C","6.18 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The pressure of a given mass of gas is 30mmHg. What will be the pressure in Newton\/m<sup>2<\/sup> ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3000Nm<sup>-2<\/sup>","3999.7Nm<sup>-2<\/sup>","309.3Nm<sup>-2<\/sup>","2984Nm<sup>-2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The magnitude to the resultant of two equal vectors, each of magnitude K units and acting at right angle to each other is _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["K","K \u221a2","\u221a2K","2K"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>An orange falls from a height of 20m. How long does it take to reach the ground ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.0 sec","0.5 sec","1 sec","4 sec"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A piece of stone weighs 80g in air, 50g when completely immersed in water and 65g in liquid Y. What is the relative density of Y ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.2","1.5","0.5","2.0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A ball is projected so as to attain maximum range. Determine the angle with which the ball must be projected.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15<sup>0<\/sup>","30<sup>0<\/sup>","60<sup>0<\/sup>","45<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A toy car of mass 8kg initially at rest is accelerated at a rate of 2m<sup>-2<\/sup> for 3 secs. The kinetic energy of the toy car is __<\/strong><\/p>","options":["144J","288J","48J","96J"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The two fixed points on a thermometer are 70cm apart. When the thermometer reads 63cm above the ice point, the temperature is_____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["63<sup>0<\/sup>C","70<sup>0<\/sup>C","90<sup>0<\/sup>C","10<sup>0<\/sup>C"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A motor-car is uniformity retarded and brought to rest from a speed of 90km\/h in 10s. Find its acceleration.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["25ms<sup>-1<\/sup>","2.5<sup>-2<\/sup>","-2.5ms<sup>2<\/sup>","-2.5ms<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Determine the quantity of heat in joules given out when a piece of iron of mass 40g and specific heat capacity 460jkg <sup>0<\/sup>C cools from 70<sup>0<\/sup>C to 40<sup>0<\/sup>C<\/strong><\/p>","options":["552J","736J","1288J","368.1"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a characteristic of the image formed in a plane mirror ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The same size as the object","As far behind the mirror as the object is in front","Real","Laterally inverted"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The angle between a plane mirror and an incident ray is 35<sup>0<\/sup>. Find the angle of reflection<\/strong><\/p>","options":["55<sup>0<\/sup>","50<sup>0<\/sup>","45<sup>0<\/sup>","70<sup>0<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A machine with a velocity ratio of 6 requires 800.1 of work to raise a load of 640 N through a vertical distance of 1 m. Find the efficiency of the machine<\/strong><\/p>","options":["It does not wet glass","It is opaque and easily seen","It can be used for extra low temperature down to -200<sup>0<\/sup>C","It is a good conductor of heat and responds rapidly to changes in temperature."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A stone whirled at the end of rope 35cm long, makes 15 complete revolutions in 4 seconds. Find the angular velocity in radians per second.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["23.6rad.s<sup>-1<\/sup>","31.4 rad.s<sup>-1<\/sup>","824.7 rad.s<sup>-1<\/sup>","942.0 rad.s<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>An object of mass 7kg is moving at a constant velocity of 20ms<sup>-1<\/sup>. Determine the kinectic energy.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["22KJ","140.KJ","1.4KJ","562.5J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the cost of operating an electric appliance for 10 hours at 30 kobo per kwh if it takes 3A when connected to a 220V supply<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N0.66","N1.32","N1.98","N2.62"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is&nbsp; not a scalar quantity ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Density","Mass","Speed","Weight"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the resultant of two forces 6N and 5N which are inclined to each other at 30<sup>0<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["12.2N","8.7N","10.6","9.5N"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT property of waves ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Refraction","Polarization","Ray box","Interference"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A battery of e.m.f. 12 volts and internal resistance 1.2 ohms is connected to an external resistance of 4 ohms. Find the current flowing in the circuit<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.3A","2.7A","3.0A","2.5A"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>An object placed 18cm in front of a convex mirror produced an image 6cm behind the mirror. Find the focal length of the mirror.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.0cm","7.5cm","-6.5","-9.0cm"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following waves is both mechanical and transverse<\/strong><\/p>","options":["X-ray","Water wave","Sound wave","Radio wave"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>PQ is a uniform metre rule pivoted at 35.0cm mark. A mass of 50g is then hung at the 15.0cm mark such than the rule balances horizontally, calculate the mass of the metre rule<\/strong><\/p>","options":["55.0g","66.7g","75.0g","77.7g"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following radiations arrangement are in their ascending order of frequency ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Y-rays, x-rays, radio waves","Radio waves, visible light,x-rays","Y-rays, radio waves, x-rays","Visible light, x-rays, radio waves"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a broadcasting station sends out waves of wavelength 400m, on what frequency is the station operatin ? (Velocity of wave-3.0 x 10<sup>8<\/sup>m\/s)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7.5 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Hz","7.5 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>Hz","1.0 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>Hz","1.0 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Hz"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The gravitional force on a mass of 1 kg at the earth's surface is 10N. Calculate the gravitational force on a satellite of mass 100kg in a circular orbit of radius 2R from the centre of the earth (R=radius of the earth)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["250N","220N","120N","110N"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following experiments confirms the existence confirms the existence of quantized energy level in an atom ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rutherford's experiment","Frank-Hertz experiment","Einstein's experiment","Lenard's experiment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The balanced lengths of a certain cell of unknown emf E' and Daniel cell of emf, 1.08V are 80.0cm and 48.0cm respectively on a potentiometer circuit, Calculate the unknown emf E'<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.5V","1.8V","2.0v","2.5v"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Doping a semi conductor with an impurity<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Decreases the conductivity","Increases the resistivity","Increases the conductivity","Has no effect"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following serves as a moderator in a nuclear reactor ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cadmium rods","Boron rods","Aluminium rods","Heavy water"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A body A moves northwards with a velocity of 5kms<sup>-1<\/sup> and another body B moves in a direction of N60<sup>0<\/sup>E with a velocity of 4<\/strong><b><span style=\"\">kms<\/span><sup style=\"\">-1<\/sup><span style=\"\">&nbsp;. What is the magnitude of the velocity of A relative to B?<\/span><\/b><\/p>","options":["2.5 kms<sup>1<\/sup>","3.5<sup>-1<\/sup>","7.8kms<sup>-1<\/sup>","8.5kms<sup>-1<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A metal sphere falling freely in a long measuring cylinder containing a liquid is under the influence of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Conservative forces only","Non-conservative forces only","Both conservative and non-conservative forces","Neither a conservative nor non-conservative force fields."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sources of energy is non-renewable ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Biomass","Solar","Wind","Tides"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The energy carried by an electromagnetic radiation depends on<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Intensity","Velocity","Mass","Frequency"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A motor journey takes 3 hours at an average speed of 120km\/h. How long will it take if the average speed is reduced to 80Km\/h ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4 hours","4.2 hours","4.5 hours","5.4 hours"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is not correct about the image formed by a pin-hole camera ? It is always<\/strong><\/p>","options":["In focus","Magnified","Real","Inverted"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the polarizing angle for a given optical material is 49<sup>0<\/sup> calculate the refractive index of the material&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.15","0.75","0.66","1.75"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two quantities that can be determined from a velocity time graph are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acceleration and work done","Retardation and distance covered","Pressure and acceleration","Mass and acceleration"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements are correct about latent heat ? It<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Causes temperature rise","Causes temperature fall","Breaks down intermolecular forces","Causes molecules to vibrate more violently"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The two most important determinants of air temperature of an area are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["evaporation and sunshine hours","wind and air mass","altitude and altitude","rainfall and humidity"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The process of adding impurity to semiconductor is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Transmutation","Doping","Polarization","Hydrolysis"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the D.C electric motor, which of the following does not apply ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Spindle","Fixed carbon brushes","Powerful magnetic field","Slip rings"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the A.C generator, which of the following does not apply ?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fixed carbon brushes","Spindle","Split rings","Powerful magnetic field"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The induction coil is a device for generating a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["High voltage from low A.C source","Low voltage from high D.C source","High voltage from a low D.C source","Low voltage from a low A.C source"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The dimension of power is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ML<sup>-1<\/sup>T<sup>-2<\/sup>","ML<sup>-2<\/sup>T<sup>-2<\/sup>","ML<sup>-2<\/sup>T<sup>-3<\/sup>","ML<sup>-1<\/sup>T<sup>-2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A body starts from rest and moves in an accelaration of 8m<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup>for 10 seconds. Find the distance during the 8<sup>th<\/sup> second.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["256m","196m","120m","60m"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Natural radioactivity was discovered by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Niel Bohr","Henri Becquerel","Del Broglie","Rutherford"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An electric lamp has the following markings 230V, 250W. How long would it take the lamp to use one kilowatt-hour when connected to a 230V mains ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8.0hr","6.0hr4","4.0hr","2.0hr"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is correct about a semi-conductor at room temperature<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The valence band is completely filled and the conduction band is partly filled","The valence band is completely filled and the conduction band is completely empty","The valence band is almost filled and the conduction band is almost empty","The valence band is empty and the conduction band is filled"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is not correct ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["When ebonite rod is rubbed with wool the ebonite rod acquires a negative charge and wool acquires a positive charge","When a glass rod is rubbed with silk the glass rod acquires a positive charge while silk acquires a negative charge","When fur is rubbed with ebonite rod the ebonite rod acquires a positive charge and fur a negative charge","When wool rubbed with an ebonite rod is brought near silk rubbed with a glass rod attraction occurs."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>With the Daniel cell, the depolarizer is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tetra-oxo-sulphate (IV) acid","Ammonium chloride solution","Copper sulphate solution","Manganese (IV) Oxide"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is not correct about the astronomical telescope under normal adjustment<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The final image is at infinity","The principal foci of the objective and eye piece coincide","The final image is at principal focus of the eye piece","The distance between the lenses is equal to the sum of their focal lengths"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the followinig colours gives the least separation when white light is dispersed by a triangular glass prism ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Red and blue","Yellow and green","Orange and Indigo","Green and Violet"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is correct about a short-sighted girl who does not put on glasses ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["She cannot see near objects clearly","Rays of light from a distant object are focused behind her retina","Her eyeball is too short","Parallel rays of light are focused in front of her retina"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is a fundamental unit<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Newton","Watt","Joule","Second"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A car moving with a speed of 90kmh<sup>-1<\/sup> was brought uniformly to rest by the application of the brakes in 10s. How far did the car travel after the brakes were applied<\/strong><\/p>","options":["125m","150m","250m","15km"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>To keep a vehicle moving at a constant speed v, requires power P, from the engine. The force provided by the engine is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["P\/V","1\/2<sup>v<\/sup>","PV","P\/V<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>An inclined plane which makes an angle of 30 with the horizontal has a velocity ratio of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","0.866","0.50"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>A stone of mass mkg is held in meters above the flour for 50s. The work done is Joules over this period is <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Mh","Mgh","0","Mgh\/50"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>The D.C. generator has essentially the same components as the A.C. generator except the presence of&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Slip-ring","Carbon brushes","Split ring","Armature"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"<p><strong>Zener diode is used for<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Power amplification","Current amplification","Voltage regulation","Energy conversion."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"}]